[♪♪♪]
[Nya] I can't believe
we're finally together, Jay.
[Kai] The team wasn't the same
without you, buddy.
[♪♪♪]
[Nya] Too bad you're a failure.
What did you say?
I said, you are a failure.
I placed my faith in you
for nothing.
You said you could capture Ras.
The only thing you've caught
is feelings.
[♪♪♪]
Face it, old man.
Even if you were once a Ninja,
you've fallen too far
for them to ever take you back.
[gasping] Uh...
uh... stay back!
You're one of us, Jay,
not them.
Aah!
[♪♪♪]
[gasping]
Meditation didn't go well?
[sighing]
Didn't find any answers,
if that's what you're asking.
Just confusion.
You sure I did this
all the time?
Seems boring.
[sighing]
You did.
You didn't always like it,
but meditation's part of
being a Ninja.
It doesn't just
hand you clear answers,
but it can process bad thoughts
to make room for better ones.
Those weren't
better thoughts, trust me.
[sighing]
Life without memories
is like
feeling around in the dark.
[Kai] Ugh,
I can't meditate either.
It's like I can't hold
a thought in this place.
I don't like it here.
We should go.
We planned to stay til dawn,
but the sun
should be up by now,
and I don't want to wait
any longer.
We need to figure out
how to get home.
I'll light the way.
[sputtering]
Dang it.
Keep forgetting our powers
are on the fritz.
This situation
just keeps getting better.
[♪♪♪]
Ooh! [gasping] What the--?
Who needs powers?
[♪♪♪]
I feel better already.
[laughing awkwardly]
Sarcasm.
Why is the ground all squishy?
[squelching]
What is that?
Is the sky... moving?
Not the sky,
those things!
[snarling]
♪ Lost in the unknown ♪
♪ So much to see ♪
♪ Jump up, kick back
whip around and spin ♪
♪ Together we will rise ♪
♪ Whip around and spin ♪
♪ For what's right ♪
[Lloyd] I'm sorry,
there must be
some kind of misunderstanding.
I'm not a Protector
of the Whispering Wood.
[Arc Dragon] You are
the Green Ninja of legend,
are you not, Lloyd,
son of Garmadon?
I am,
but I've never even heard
of this place.
[roaring]
Do not lie to us.
You must have felt the call...
but you ignored it.
The first Green Ninja
to ever abandon their duties,
to neglect the wood
from which mortal Life itself
originally sprang forth!
There have been
other Green Ninja?
The prophecy never said
anything about--
[Arc Dragon] Of course
there have been others,
and each one has performed
the Ritual of Unrooting
to maintain the power
of this wood,
until you!
I didn't know any of this.
I thought I'd reached
my true potential!
You believe you only have
one true potential?
That any of us do?
Hey, go easy!
Lloyd protected this place
as soon as he got here.
He saved these little guys
from some weird monster dudes!
Too little, too late.
Without the Master of Life,
the Whispering Wood
has weakened,
its light dimmed.
I swear to you,
I-I had no idea.
All the other Life Masters
found their way here
as soon as they came of age.
"Came of age"?
A stage of maturation
for mortals.
The transition
out of childhood.
Oh... that must be the reason.
When I was a kid,
there was an incident
with Tomorrow's Tea,
and poof,
I was instantly a teenager.
I guess I...
never really came of age.
[quietly] Did you know that?
He skipped
part of his childhood?
[quietly] No idea.
Gotta say, that's messed up.
I see. You say
your aging was... unnatural.
We have been angry with you
for so long, Life Master.
Truly, you could not have known
what was needed of you.
We...
apologize.
I never imagined my rapid aging
would have consequences
for anyone except me.
The day you were exposed
to that tea
was the day our fate,
and the fate of this wood,
was sealed.
[Wyldfyre]
Are you two done yet?
We gotta get back
to the Monastery
and figure out
why my power's all wonky.
Our powers
are acting weird too.
You don't see us
worrying about it.
[Wyldfyre]
Yeah, but my powers are cool.
If shaking the dumb ground
or building robot vacuums
was the only thing I could do...
[snorting] I wouldn't
be bothered either.
Relax.
We've earned a vacation.
We just stopped
an undead dragon.
Besides,
how would we leave here
even if we wanted to, Wyldfyre?
We haven't seen anyone else,
we have no way to contact
the other Ninja...
The other Ninja.
Oh, wow. I really hope
everyone's okay.
We should probably head back.
We just need to...
[bushes rustling]
[sniffing]
[growling]
[meowing]
[Sora] Cats?
Yes!
[meowing]
No, no, no, I'm allergic!
I'll swell up
like a puffer fish!
[meowing]
Or...
maybe my allergies are cured?
-This place is purr...fect!
-[cats purring]
[Wyldfyre groans]
[creature snarling]
[Kai] I got this!
Not our first time
facing flying creeps!
[Jay] Why you gotta keep
rubbing it in?
I don't remember anything!
[power shorting out]
-[Nya yelping]
-[Jay] Nya!
[Jay struggles]
[mech suit creaking]
[grunting with effort]
Whoa!
[grunting with impact]
[Nya struggles]
[groaning and yelping]
Whoa! Aah!
[creature snarling]
[screaming]
Aah!
[♪♪♪]
-Whoa!
-[creature splatting]
[gasping]
Why is this cave so... wet?
[creatures snarling]
[Jay gagging]
[groaning]
I don't think it's a cave!
[ground rumbling]
[Kai] What is that?
An earthquake?
Oh no. Grab onto something!
Grab something?
Do you know
how slimy everything is?
[rumbling]
-[belching rumble]
-[Kai and Nya yelping]
Whoa! Whoa...
[grunting with effort]
It smells horrible.
Aah!
I can't believe
I'm about to say these words,
but I'm pretty sure
we're in a Quealiche's stomach!
What's a Quealiche?
Enormous slug-like creatures
that burrow through
the Land of Madness.
I was briefly transferred
to the Decontamination Chamber
in the Administration,
and had to hose off agents
unlucky enough to run into one.
I'd know this stench anywhere!
[grunting with effort]
You mean that gust of wind
was a... belch?
Oh, gross.
How did the Monastery
end up inside the belly
of a giant slug
in the Land of Madness?
[Kai] Bigger question,
how do we get out?
Preferably
before we get digested.
[Jay] Only two options,
so I vote we find its mouth!
Grab on!
[♪♪♪]
[creature snarling]
Oh! [chuckling] Thank you.
[♪♪♪]
You're worried about Lloyd.
[Arin] All this new info
about who he's supposed to be,
it's gotta be overwhelming.
Like a nightmare
where you have a test
you didn't study for.
I wish there was
something I could do.
Arin, you're the only one
without Elemental Powers.
Thanks, Euphrasia. Rub it in.
I mean, it's an advantage.
You're the most dependable
at the moment.
You've never had powers,
and you don't need them.
Lloyd will rely on you now
more than ever.
[Lloyd] This thing
you needed me to do...?
[Arc Dragon]
The Rite of Unrooting.
It maintains the Wood.
Maintains?
[Arc Dragon]
All Realms are connected,
even before the Merge.
Like water through roots,
or bees spreading pollen,
Source Energy flows
through unseen paths
across every land
and all people.
To maintain the Whispering Wood
is to cleanse those pathways,
to sustain the connection
between all life.
Okay.
I'm late, but I'm here now.
How do I perform this rite?
[Arc Dragon]
I wish it were possible.
While the Rite teaches you
the truth
about the Green Ninja's
Elemental Powers,
the time has passed.
One as old as you
would never survive it.
Your roots have spread
too deep and too wide
to change your current path.
It would teach me
the truth about my powers?
I've never fully
understood them.
I've been called
the Master of Power,
the Master of Energy.
Nothing ever really fit.
Sometimes I didn't really fit.
It is energy, but... what kind?
It doesn't burn like fire,
or shock like lightning.
[Arc Dragon]
Would you name a flower
from the shape of its seed?
Know the lean of a tree
before it is planted?
The mystical nature
of your sudden aging
stunted your powers.
The potential
has not fully blossomed.
Well, now it may never.
Something is wrong
with all our Elemental Powers.
[Arc Dragon] I am aware.
Some of the Source Dragons
have withdrawn their connection
to the Merged Lands.
That's why the powers
of Elemental Masters
are unreliable.
Wait... seriously?
[Arc Dragon] Yes.
Sadly, our own Source, Life,
is one of those who no longer
nourishes the land,
and so, the decline
of the Whispering Wood
will soon quicken.
Our end is at hand.
But why would--
Oh, no. This is my fault!
I had my team summon
the Arc Dragon of Focus.
I was warned
it might anger them,
but I had no choice.
[Arc Dragon]
Withdrawn Source energy,
unbalanced elemental powers--
if only the Rite
had been performed,
the power of the Master of Life
might have overcome
all of this.
All my life,
I've been pushed
in so many directions...
prophecies, destiny, visions.
I can't always tell
what I'm choosing to do
or what fate
is forcing me to do,
but if there's even a chance
to stabilize Source Energy
while saving this wood,
then I choose to take that risk.
[Kai] It's not smelling
any better.
[Nya grunts with effort]
[Kai] Pretty sure this is
the way to the mouth.
[tendrils slapping]
[Kai] We're not gonna make it!
[Jay] Oh, yes, we are.
Nya, flood the stomach.
Kai, turn up the heat.
A little heartburn is just
what the doctor ordered.
[Nya grunts with effort]
H'yah!
[creatures screeching]
[Kai grunting with effort]
Oh, man, not now.
[Jay groaning] I was hoping
it wouldn't come to this.
-[beeping remote]
-Goodbye, my friend.
[Kai] Which one of us
is he talking to?
-Ah!
-[Nya gasping]
[countdown timer beeping]
[countdown beeping accelerating]
[explosion]
[Nya] Sorry.
I know you loved that thing.
[Jay sighs]
Guess I love living more.
[deep rumbling]
[gurgling belch]
[Jay] It worked!
Get ready for it.
[Kai] Get ready for what?
Get ready for what?!
[thundering wave,
all screaming]
[dragons snoring]
[ground rumbling]
[rumbling]
[explosive roaring]
[gurgling and bellowing]
[vomiting]
[screaming]
[grunting with impact]
[Nya gasps] Ew!
I can't believe that worked!
[Kai groans]
I forgot how messy
hanging out with you
could be, Jay.
[Jay] Don't anyone
celebrate too soon.
[growling]
[Kai]
These aren't the same dragons
we ran into last time, are they?
[Nya] They are,
and they're not happy
we woke them up.
[roaring]
How am I
supposed to guide us out
when it's dawn
in every direction?
[Sora] Maybe we're not
supposed to leave.
Where'd those cats
even come from?
-Why does that matter?
-[cats purring]
Can't you just
enjoy something for once?
[gasping in delight]
Pie!
[munching]
Hmm. They're a little cold.
Huh...
That wasn't there a second ago.
but I'm glad it's here now!
You guys
don't think it's strange
your favorite thing is pies,
and then there's pies?
And your favorite thing is cats,
and then there's cats?
[Riyu grumbles]
[cats meowing]
-[Sora] No.
-[Frak] No.
Ah! Pies are not supposed
to grow on bushes!
Wyldmelons can't grow
outside the Wyldness!
This place is full of trickery!
[panting angrily]
[sniffing]
[grumbling curiously]
[grumbling]
You got a scent?
[grumbling language]
An unusual scent?
-Maybe it's a way out of here.
-Whoa!
Let's go.
[Sora groans in disappointment]
-[cats meowing]
-Oh...
[cats meowing]
[Jay] Even
in the middle of nowhere,
you two have enemies?
[grunting in combat]
[Jay] Why am I hanging out
with you people?
[dragons grunting]
[suit damage alert beeping]
[♪♪♪]
[countdown timer beeping]
[Kai] Buddy, you're running out
of things to blow up.
[countdown timer accelerating]
Whoa!
[Kai] Come on!
[Nya] Wait!
[dragons snarling]
[Jay gasps]
[Jay] I can't do Spinjitzu!
I can't do Spinjitzu!
[panicked voice echoing]
[gasping]
[roaring]
[dragon squeaking]
[dragon roaring]
[Jay] I'm fine!
-[Kai] Over-under!
-[Jay] What-what?
[roaring]
[Kai] It's what it sounds like.
[Jay yelping, dragon roaring]
[Kai] H'yah! H'up!
[dragon roaring]
H'yah!
[Nya] What now?
[Kai] You could try apologizing.
[Nya] Me?
They literally chased you!
[Kai] Let's use their anger
against them.
[Nya] Hey, dirt-eater!
I've seen bigger horns
on a tricycle!
[Kai] Earth Dragon?
More like Barf Dragon!
[roaring]
[grunting with effort]
[laughing]
Man, that felt good!
Working like that
jog any memories, Jay?
No!
You two share a look
and know what
the other's thinking.
I can't even remember
how to do Spinjitzu,
which seems like
the bare minimum
to call yourself a Ninja.
Even that kid
with no powers can do it.
That's what training's for.
Even we have to train.
There's always room to grow.
[sighing] You don't get it.
I hated working
for the Administration.
I lost in the Tournament
of Sources.
I was only a pretty good
bounty hunter.
So?
So? No more failures.
If I'm gonna be a Ninja,
I need to be a great one.
It's another reason
I need to remember
my forgotten memories.
I don't know how,
I don't know
if it's even possible,
but I have to.
We'll help you.
Whoa...
[Wyldfyre] What is this thing?
[Sora] Actually...
I have no idea.
It's definitely not normal.
Well, in we go.
Whoa!
I'm not jumping into
some mystery black hole
just cause you said so.
I agree with Frak.
There's no rush
to leave this place.
It has everything we need.
Yeah, which isn't normal.
It has to be a trap!
It wants us to stay here forever!
No, that's a trap.
Totally.
Now, where was that pie bush?
The pie bush is a trap,
you clown-faces!
Don't you see what this place
is doing to you?
[together] No.
[sighing]
This is for your own good.
[shrieking] Yaah!
-Whoa!
-Wha...!
[gasping]
Perfect!
[Frak wails]
You're the one who's not
in her right mind, Wyldfyre.
[Frak] You should really
listen to us.
Hold on.
Take a deep breath
and calm down.
You don't get to tell me
to calm down!
[roaring]
[grunting in combat]
[groaning]
[roaring]
[grunting with effort]
Why are you smiling?
We have you beat.
Aw... you two teamed up.
Cute,
but I always team up
with dragons.
[roaring]
Ah!
[all wailing]
[Arc Dragon] Deep within
the Whispering Wood
is the Temple
of the Green Ninja.
Inside, you will be guided
to perform
the Rite of Unrooting.
The temple is hidden,
even from the eyes and ears
of the forest.
[Lloyd] Then...
how will we find it?
[Arc Dragon]
If you are meant to,
it will call to you,
but I must warn you again,
the journey on which
you are about to embark
will be treacherous.
That's not enough to stop me.
[♪♪♪]
[wailing]
[grunting with impact]
Ah!
Welcome to Umbrasilvis.
Wait a second...
pies don't grow on bushes!
And where did
those cats come from?
[sighing] I...
I don't know what came over us.
[sighing]
There was something
seriously off about that place.
Thanks for guiding us out.
I guess you do make
a pretty good leader.
My dragon heritage
probably made me immune
to whatever got into your heads.
Riyu wasn't affected either.
I may have heroically
gotten us out of there,
which some might say
is the most heroic thing
ever done.
[sighing]
But where are we now?
[doors slamming]
[Frak] Friendly place.
[Sora] Look, over there.
[♪♪♪]
Maybe we can hitch a ride
back to Ninjago
on that airship.
That's an Explorer's Club ship.
They're probably in the middle
of an important expedition.
Too busy to help.
Let's find another way home.
I'm sure this place has tons
of public transportation options.
[slamming doors]
[♪♪♪]
I, uh, think I dropped
something back by the well.
Is everything okay?
[voice] Frak, is that you?
[muttering]
Doesn't he look like--
[sighing awkwardly]
Hi, Dad.
[♪♪♪]